# GEETHANJALI VEETIL

PHONE: 0459-215-817 | EMAIL: Geethanjali.tv@gmail.com | Melbourne, VIC

LINKEDIN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/geethanjali-veetil/

GITHUB: <a href="https://github.com/Gveetil">https://github.com/Gveetil</a> | PORTFOLIO: <a href="https://gveetil.github.io">https://gveetil.github.io</a>

#### **PROFILE**

Full Stack Web Developer with a strong background in software product design and development. Certificate from Monash University Coding Bootcamp in full-stack web Technologies. Prior work experience with Microsoft .Net technologies like C# and databases (SQL Server).

On a personal level, I have always enjoyed programming and I love a good challenge. I am patient and persevering, and that helps me work through tough problems as I don't give up easily. My background in software development combined with my technical aptitude in web technologies makes me a valued addition to any team.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

React, Node.js, Express, MySQL, MongoDB, JavaScript, jQuery, GIT & GitHub, Material UI, CSS, HTML, Bootstrap, Materialize, JSON

### **PROJECTS**

### Learn@Home

- Learn@Home is a home schooling solution that helps teachers and students stay up to date with their lessons and homework.
- This application is developed using the MERN stack React and Material UI for the front end, Node.js with Express server, MySQL and sequelize ORM on the backend.
- Also used express-sessions and passport middleware to authenticate users, and dropbox API for uploading and saving files.
- Worked independently on this project.

Application: <a href="https://learn-at-home.herokuapp.com/">https://learn-at-home.herokuapp.com/</a> GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/Gveetil/Learn-At-Home">https://github.com/Gveetil/Learn-At-Home</a>

### **Google Books Search**

- Google Books Search lets you browse and locate books you like, save books to review or purchase later.
- This application is developed using the MERN stack React and Material UI for the front end, Node.js with Express server, mongoDB and mongoose on the backend.
- Also uses Google Books API for fetching books and SocketIO for messaging.
- Worked independently on this project.

Application: <a href="https://gveetil-books-search.herokuapp.com/">https://gveetil-books-search.herokuapp.com/</a> GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/Gveetil/Google-Books-Search">https://github.com/Gveetil/Google-Books-Search</a>

### **Lets Talk Corona**

- Lets Talk Corona is a blogging platform where users share stories about the pandemic.
- We used Materialize library, jQuery, Node.js with Express server, MySQL database and Seguelize ORM. Used express-sessions and passport middleware to authenticate users.
- Worked as a team of two; My role included developing the application's user interface and integrating the passport middleware. Also set up linting and Travis CI to test and deploy the application to Heroku.

Application: <a href="https://lets-talk-corona.herokuapp.com/">https://lets-talk-corona.herokuapp.com/</a></a>
<a href="https://github.com/dev-hg20/lets-talk-corona">https://github.com/dev-hg20/lets-talk-corona</a></a>

### **Employee Directory**

- This application provides a centralized searchable employee directory where users can browse, sort and locate employee details.
- Worked independently on this project.
- Built using React, Bootstrap and a JSON data file.

Application: <a href="https://gveetil.github.io/React-Employee-Directory/">https://gveetil.github.io/React-Employee-Directory/</a> GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/Gveetil/React-Employee-Directory/">https://github.com/Gveetil/React-Employee-Directory/</a>

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Mineman Systems, Melbourne, VIC - Software Consultant

Nov 2010 to Feb 2013

- Maintained and optimized the Mineman product (C#).
- Migrated application code base from VSS to TFS, set up backup and recovery processes.
- Designed and implemented integration of Barcode Scanners, Weigh Scales and Barcode Printers into the Mineman application.

### **Symphony Services**, Bangalore, India - Lead - Product Development

Nov 2005 to Jul 2010

- Designed and implemented many key modules in the Assortment and Replenishment Planner (C#).
- Optimized application performance using memory profiling tools (ANTS).
- Trained and mentored junior team members.
- Evaluated and resolved end user issues.

### E5 Systems, Bangalore, India - Technical Specialist

Feb 2001 to Nov 2005

- Designed and implemented several modules in the Providus RiskResolve (VB.Net), and the Seisuins Business Continuity System (C#) products.
- Awarded employee of the year(2004) for my work with Installshield.
- Awarded team of the year(2001) for customizing in4Suite to the real estate industry.
- Mapped high level functional requirements as part of an onsite team based in Chicago and Washington, US.

### **Equinox Solutions,** Bangalore, India - *Software Engineer*

Feb 1999 to Jan 2001

- Worked out of London, UK with August Group, to maintain a document management application used by Bank of America. (VB, Filenet Panagon IDM)
- Developed ActiveX controls and interfaces to extend Compaq's Work Expeditor Product.(VB)

### **EDUCATION**

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate: Monash University, Melbourne, VIC

C-DAC Diploma in Advanced Computing: Pune University, India

Bachelor of Computer Science: Bangalore University, India